Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Professional Correspondence Files, 1910-1952
  - (J), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    R. H. Jones, Walter P. Johnson, (inclusion of EER on Arbitration Board).
  - (K), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 122)
    Stanford Education Conferences (July), Grayson N. Kefauver, A. C. Krey (summer appointment), The Kiplinger Washington Letter (12/37).
  - (L), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 123)
    Ralph Lutz, Thomas LaFargue,
  - (Mc), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 124)
    R. McKinney, F. L. McElroy (Alumni conference), Beverly McAnear, Alonzo G. McFarland.
  - (M), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 125)
    M. Madison, H. E. Marsh (speaking engagement), University Guidance Service, T. Mitchell.
  - (N), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    Mary L. Norton, recommendation of Harley Notter, New History Society, National Cyclopedia of American Biography.
  - (O), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    C. M. O'Hara.
  - (P), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    W. H. Pillsbury.
  - (R), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    J.P. Bretz, Alice Rose, H. E. rensch, ( A Tentative Plan of Study Under the Proposed Historic Mining Towns research Foundation). F. M. Bollinger, C. H. Rowell, George C. Robinson, Agreement for Independent Study at Stanford, Harry B. reynolds, J. F. Rippy (AHA), W. T. Root, Stanford Radio Committee, Easton Rothwell.
  - (S), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    Merrill Spalding, Max Savelle (Microfilming Maryland Gazette), Lou N. Small (Radio), C. C. Scott, Charles n. Spinks, Dick Strouse, R. L. Wilbur, David H. Stevens, American Legion, H. W. Swafford, Victoria Schmuck, C. Sweet (American Legion Mother's Day Ceremony), Stanford Day at 1939 Golden Gate Exhibition, L. F. LeFeure, R. E. Swain, J. W. Shannon, E. C. Stewart (Thomas Paine), recommendation of Savelle to Guggenheim Foundation, J. E. W. Sterling, San Quentin Prison Dept. of Education, Homer R. Spence.
  - (T), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    English-Speaking Union, M. Thorne, United Brotherhood-Tolerance Movements, D. E. Trueblood, P. H. Taylor, Harold Temperley, Independent Study and Guidance, Memorandum for Meetings (Feb. 7 & Feb. 11, 1938), Max Thelen, Harold F. Taggart, P. J. Treat.
  - (U), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - (V), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    D. R. Van Patten, Nathan Van Patten
  - (W), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    Purpose of Stanford (Letters to R. L. Wilbur), Letters re B. C. Weber, R. L. Wilbur, Harry Winton, Gordon Wright, Dorothea Wyatt, Guidance Service (Letter to Wilbur), Oscar O. Winther, Lynn White, Jr., W. A. Wood, Jr., Sire E. Wrench, C. F. Weigle, J. P. Weter, Edward White, Oscar O. Winther, Account to Wilbur of happenings during brief absence, Arrangements for Superior Students, O. H. Wedel, Analysis of the 1888 Presidential Election (Lawrence reed), WPA Historical records Survey.
  - (XYZ), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    C. C. Young
  - (A), 1938-39 (Box 11, Folder 136)
    recommendations regarding assistants in instruction, David Harris (re Irwin Abrams), Robert C. Binkley (Joint Committee on Materials for research), P. B. Albright, Stanford Alumni Conference, Education 222: The American College and University.
  - ( American Historical Association), 1938-39 (Box 11, Folder 137)
    Memo re suggested functions and activities of the Committee on Historical Source Materials of the AHA contained in a letter from Herbert A. Keller to Robert C. Binkley Jan. 12, 1939, appointment of EER to Committee on Historical Source Materials, F. H. Herrick, C. F. Brand.
  - (B), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    Roy Bell, Charles A. Barker, Hans Baron, Harold W. Bradley, David K. Bjork, E. M. Earle (re T. A. Bailey's invitation to Princeton Institute for advanced study), T. A. Bailey, Arnold Brecht, Philip Bancroft, Russell Buchanan.
  - (C), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    Karl M. Cowdery, Mills College Institute of International relations, F. W. Boardman, Jr., Manoel Cardozo, Lottie G. Woods (Colonial Dames of America), E. A. Cottrell (Social Science research Funds), Sir Arthur Willert, Leland T. Chapin, Merle Curti, Calif. Association for Adult Education, Conference on Adult Education, CBS Broadcast: The People's Platform.
  - (D), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    W. H. Davis (University Press), Death of Frank P. Deering, Edith Dobie, Dictionary of American History (includes EER's articles), Vocational Guidance Committee, F. P. Deering, Letter to Paul H. Davis re establishment of an Institute of American History, C. A. Duniway, Joseph S. Davis ( Agricultural Problems and Policy).
  - (E), 1938 - 39 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    C. Dey Elkus, Grayson N. Kefauver
  - (English Speaking Union), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    National Meeting, T. D. Boardman, Trip to S. California, Minutes of Meetings of Executive Committee, F. B. Malim, Democracy in the Present Day World) (John W. Davis), George Young, Travel Service, report of Activities of California Branch, Evelyn Wrench, Grace L. Doren.
  - (F), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    Eugene Field Society, Guy S. Ford
  - (G), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    John Gange, Geneva Junior Year, regulations of the Committee on Graduate Study concerning the Distributed Minor, S. H. Gill, Sept. 30, 1938, Meeting of Committee on Graduate Study, Ralph H. Gabriel, J. D. Grant
  - (H), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 145)
    John P. Herrick, J. B. Havre, David Harris, Calif. Bankers' Association Convention, Franklin Hichborn, Wolfgang Hallgarten.
  - (I - J), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    Jessie K. Jordan
  - (K), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    George Knoles, Grayson N. Kefauver, Mary Sweet, A. J. Kraus, C. Killingsworth, Max Kohnstamm, A. C. Krey, R. J. Kerner.
  - (L), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    Henry R. Luce, A Guérard, Albert J. Lynd (Work in Medieval History, especially in Belgium), Lonstreet Memorial Association, Thomas LaFargue.
  - (Mc), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 149)
    Beverly McAnear.
  - (M), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 150)
    Henry Madden, C. E. Martin, Dudley Moorhead, Elizabeth Margo.
  - (N), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 151)
    The Origins of the Foreign Policies of Woodrow Wilson (by Harley Notter)
  - (O - P), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 152)
    Frank J. Palmer (We vote as we Please), N. Van Patten, El Campo De Los Sonoraenses: Tres Anos de residencia en California 1849-1851 by Guillermo Perkins, Leland W. Cutter, D. L. Palmer, Bessie L. Pierce, H. I. Priestly.
  - (R), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 153)
    Easton Rothwell (employment), Alice Rose, note on John D. Works Collection, Stanford Radio Program, San Francisco Employers Council, Thoreau Raymond, Emily Ross, Junior Statesmen of America, W. T. Root, J. F. Rippy.
  - (S), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 154)
    Max Savelle, What Might Have Been (Column for Stanford Daily), Savelle's comments on preventing war, C. Nelson Spinks, James Shannon, Victoria Schuck, Charles C. Scott (Final report on research in Belgium)
  - (T), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 155)
    Harold F. Taggart R. Terrill, D. Elton Trueblood, D. P. Trude (info re former Western Pioneer Guide)
  - (V), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 156)
    San Francisco Town Hall Forum (Carl Van Doren), N. Van Patten (re Time).
  - (W), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 157)
    J. B. Weter Award, Merrill Jensen, R. L. Wilbur, Ernest O. Holland (re Bernard Weber), Lynn White (New History A. B. Minor requirements), Edward White, request for Sabbatical leave, Dorothea Wyatt, Memorandum to Wilbur concerning need for a University Historian, James T. Watkins, Mary W. Williams, Evelyn Wrench, William H. Waste, Oscar O. Winther, World Alliance for International Friendship through the Churches.
  - (XYZ), 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - (A), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 159)
    Universal Military Training, Henry M. Adams, American Council of Learned Societies - Committee on research and Teaching Personnel (Spring meeting, 1940), American Union for Concerted Peace Efforts, Stanford Sentinal (opposing Foreign relief - signed by Theodore Dreiser), Death of Wallace Alexander.
  - (B), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 160)
    Louis H. Bean ( Ballot Behavior), Barlow V. Bowen, Margery Bailey, Charles A. Barker, T. A. Bailey (work at Princeton in Washington), death of Robert C. Binkley, Frances Barney, Earl Warren, T. S. Barclay, Russell Buchanan, Edward McMahon (re Harold W. Bradley).
  - (C), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 161)
    Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, Benjamin F. Hardy, W. Henry Cooke, Manoel S. Cardozo, Speaking Engagements, M. Graves (re Waldo Chamberlin), (Paul F. Cruikshank), Palo Alto Times, California Association for Adult Education, R. C. Clark, Paul H. Clyde.
  - (D), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 162)
    Paul H. Davis Women's Vocational Committee, (Marshall Dill, Jr.), (J. L. Delkin), Allen Drury, George Ditz (Stanford Days), Deep Well Guest Ranch
  - (E), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 163)
    Evolution of American Political Parties.
  - (F), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 164)
    (Lisette Fast), H. H. Fisher, George W. Frasier.
  - (G), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 165)
    John Grange (suggestion for fund-raising), General Education Board, Sumner Gill.
  - (H), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 166)
    (Paul L. Hanna), David Harris (Leave of Absence), E. V. Hollis, A. C. Hoffman, Herbert Hoover, Huntington Library, Paul H. Davis, Paul L. Hanna, J. P. Hoover, Edward M. Hulme, Nomination of H. Hoover for Noble Peace Prize, Hazel D. Hansen (return from Greece).
  - (IJK), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 167)
    Independent Study, Jessie K. Jordan, Herbert A. Kellar (Protection of Archives in war zones), Grayson N. Kefauver, George Knoles (re Chairmanship of History of Western Civilization Course), American Education Forum (Radio Broadcasts on Democracy and Education, A. C. Krey, F. J. Klingberg, Teacher Preparation.
  - (L), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 168)
    Aid to Allies, Robin Lampson, Julian Lesser, M. Lawrence (re Use of Borel Collection), WPA Inventory of American Imprints Project, Albert J. Lynd (Hasty Departure from Europe).
  - (M), 139-40 (Box 13, Folder 169)
    D. T. Moorhead, Beverly McAnear, Henry Madden, P. A. Martin, Stanford National Emergency Committee, T. Mitchell, C. F. Marsh.
  - (N), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 170)
    Needham Papers.
  - (P), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 171)
    [Edward Parsons (?)], (John Pelényi).
  - 139-50 (Q-R) (Box 13, Folder 172)
    Howard H. Quint, Conference on Radio and Education, J. C. Russell, J. Fred Rippy, E. Rothwell, Royal Historical Society, I. G. Richardson (re Pacific Southwest Conference on Adult Education), A. Rose.
  - (S), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 173)
    V. Schuck, Merrill Spalding, Social Science research Council of the Pacific Coast, M. Savelle (re Problem dismissing instructors because of Budget Difficulties), Stanford Fund.
  - (T), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 174)
    M. Thorne, Time Magazine, William W. Tinsley.
  - (U - V), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 175)
    Unitarian Laymen's League, N. Van Patten.
  - (W), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 176)
    J. B. Weter Award, Oscar O. Winter, (Chairmanship of Public Exercises Committee), Lynn White ( A report on the Future of History at Stanford), J. Watrous, W. L. Westermann, J. A. Whitfield, (citizenship course), H. G. Warren, J. D. Russell (1940 Institute for Administrative Officers of Higher Institutions), Edward White, Mary W. Williams, D. Wyatt, B. C. Weber, F. C. Wooton, Colonial Dames of America, The Non-Partisan Committee for Peace through revision of the Neutrality Law, J. T. Watkins.
  - (XYZ), 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - (A), 1940-41 (Box 13, Folder 178)
    The Future of Humanistic Education, Merle Alderman, The American Association for State and Local History, 9th Annual Stanford Alumni Conference.
  - (B), 1940-41 (Box 13, Folder 179)
    William Bark, Charles A. Barker, Speaking Engagements, (1832 Election).
  - (C), 1940-41 (Box 13, Folder 180)
    H. Craig, Council Against Intolerance in America, (Wal do Chamberlin), E. A. Cottrell, K. M. Cowdery (registrar's co-operation with Selective service system), H. Clodius, Manoel S. Cardozo, Colonial Dames of America, Speaking Engagements, L. M. Lissner.
  - (Commonwealth Club Project), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 181)
    Defense of the Pacific Coast, Notes on Studies Currently Under Way In The Field Of International relations, much Correspondence & Mimeograph Material (especially by Stuart Ward) re Commonwealth Club research project policies and preparations for current project), National Defense and Political Science by Edward M. Earle.
  - (D), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 182)
    Grace L. Dorey (English - Speaking Union), P. H. Davis (Stanford Annual Appeal), John W. Dodds (Proposal for establishment of a School of Humanities), Monroe E. Deutsch (Commonwealth Club), Allen Drury.
  - (E), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 183)
    Charles De Y. Elkus, Edward M. Earle
  - (Education Conferences), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 184)
    Paul R. Hanna
  - (Executive Committee), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - (English - Speaking Union), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 186)
    EER's resignation from presidency, Executive Meetings, Grace L. Dorey, (Sir Firoz-kahn Noon), relief to Britain, Frank Coan, Evelyn Wrench.
  - (F), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 187)
    H. H. Fisher (Room utilization in Hoover Library), Fellowship of Conciliation.
  - (G), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 188)
    R. P. Grinnell, John Grange, Save-the-redwoods League, A. Guerard (Visit of an Emperor),
  - (H), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 189)
    David Harris (including Book review), Herbert Hoover, Gray C. Boyce, W. R. Hitchcock, Carlton Hayes, Paul R. Hanna.
  - (I), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 190)
    Immigration
  - (J), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 191)
    Joffre Debates, H. C. Jones.
  - (K), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 192)
    R. Kerner
  - (L), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 193)
    C. D. Leake, Albert J. Lynd.
  - (Mc), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 194)
    Beverly McAnear, American Defense - Harvard Group.
  - (M), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 195)
    H. A. Mason, Dudley Moorhead, T. W. Mitchell, Klaus Mehnert, C. H. Hunter, John S. Millis, P. A. Martin, Anatole G. Mazour, Mills College Institute of International relations.
  - (N), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 196)
    Northern California Junior College Association, National resources Planning Board, National Youth Administration Aid, Social Science research Council (Classifying Historians), Northern California - Nevada International relations Clubs' Conference.
  - (Northern California Committee for Federal Union), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 197)
    Mauncey D.
  - (O), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 198)
    Dwayne Orton (President of Stockton J. C.)
  - (P), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 199)
    Philological Association of Stanford, Frederic L. Paxson (American Civilization course at U. C.), Influenza Epidemic.
  - (Q - R), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 200)
    Howard H. Quint, list of EER's addresses, E. Rothwell, Harley Notter (work in State Dept.), H. E. rensch, Commonwealth Club Radio Program.
  - (S), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 201)
    Max Savelle, H. Sprout, A Union of Peoples and a Federation of War, Elizabeth Selder, Social Science research Council of the Pacific Coast, J. E. W. Sterling, Merrill Spalding, R. E. Swain.
  - (Stanford Alumni), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 202)
    Unveiling of Wilbur portrait.
  - (Stanford Fiftieth Year Commemoration), 1940-41 (Box 14, Folder 203)
    Newspaper Clippings, Programs, Minutes of Planning Meetings, Stanford Today, Suggestions, R. E. Swain, Committees.
  - (T), 1940-41 (Box 15, Folder 204)
    Eileen Tuxford's resignation
  - (V), 1940-41 (Box 15, Folder 205)
    Monterey County League of Women Voters.
  - (W), 1940-41 (Box 15, Folder 206)
    relation of Hist. Dept. to School of Social Sciences (letter to Wilbur), James T. Watkins, B. C. Weber, John H. Watrous, Jr, R. L. Wilbur, Dorothea Wyatt, Lynn T. White, regional Conference for Higher Education, Oscar O. Winther, Lottie G. Woods (Colonial Dames of America), Y. Winters (re Henry B. Parkes), Edward White, Albert B. White.
  - (A), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 207)
    Frank Aydelotte, AHA Special Subcommittee on Newspapers, Henry M. Adams.
  - (Alumni Conference), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - (B), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 209)
    Margery Bailey (conflict with H. Heffner on use of theater), Copy of letter establishing Margaret Byring Professorship, Speech by Adolf A. Berle, Jr. on Books in Wartime, Harold W. Bradley, William Cl Bark.
  - (C), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 210)
    Leland W. Cutler, Manoel S. Cardozo, L. B. Kinnaird, Death of E. P. Cubberley, Waldo Chamberlin, Univ. of Chicago Fiftieth Anniversary.
  - (Civiliam Defense Council - personal) minutes of meetings, Alfred R. Master, Procedures, air raid shelters., 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - (D), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 212)
    Monroe E. Deutsch, John W. Dodds, Godfrey Davies.
  - (E), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 213)
    Paul C. Edwards, Edward M. Earle, English-Speaking Union.
  - (F), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 214)
    Federal Union, Inc., H.H. Fisher, Guy S. Ford.
  - (Faith and the University), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 215)
    Ralph H. Gabriel, John Gange, Monroe E. Deutsch, Herbert Hoover.
  - (Committee on Family relations), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 216)
  - (G), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 217)
    John Gange, Comments on proposed war course (Letter to Wilbur), R. R. Gros, Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching (Independent Study), F. W. Ganzert
  - (General Education in War and Peace), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 218)
  - (H), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 219)
    Hubert Heffner (Use of Memorial Hall), Margery Bailey, David Harris, Carlton J. H. Hayes, Charles Hodges, Herbert Hoover (re book which he is co-authoring), H. D. Jones (re Franklin Hichborn Papers) Edward W. Hazen Foundation (Conversations on religion in Higher Education), Stanford Futures Gift Plan, recommendations of W. R. Hitchcock.
  - (I), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 220)
    Yamatu Ichihashi (Legal Problems), Studies of the Foreign relations and Military Policies of the United States (at Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton), Mills College Institute of International relations, Monroe E. Deutsch (San Francisco International Center).
  - (J), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 221)
    War Damage Insurance, Jessie K. Jordan
  - (K), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 222)
    Robert J. Kerner (Congressional Appropriations for Printing of Documents), George Knoles, A. C. Krey.
  - (L), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 223)
    J. F. Rippy (re Men for position at Stanford), Thomas LaFargue.
  - (M), 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 224)
    Eliot G. Mears, R. L. Wilbur, Dudley T. Moorhead, Albert J. Lynd, Death of P. A. Martin, Paul G. Miller, Henry Madden, High School Academic Preparation (Letter to J. P. Mitchell), Dean E. McHenry, Max Savelle (History of Western Civilization)
  - (Mc), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - (N), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 226)
    Harley Notter, H. F. Taggart (re T. Nunan), Curtis P. Nettels (re AHA Luncheon) Charles E. Nowell, John R. Nichols (re American Field Service).
  - (National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies) Herbert Hoover., 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - (O -P), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 228)
    American Defense - Harvard Group, Yvor Winters (re H. B. Parkes), Frederic L. Paxson, Pacific House.
  - (Q - R), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 229)
    W. T. Root, Easton Rothwell, H. B. reynolds, Letters re Alice Rose, Speaking Engagements, Russian War relief Inc.
  - (Publications by EER), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 230)
    Speech at unveiling of Wilbur Portrait; A Stanford Man in America.
  - (S), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 231)
    Stanford Emergency Conservation School, Edward Steen, Nelson Spinks, Merrill Spalding, Max Savelle (Trip to Mexico; History of Western Civilization), Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Fellowships at Stanford), Social Science research Council, G. C. Sellery (Problems and Future of Liberal - Arts Education), Engel Sluiter, Memo to J. H. Polhemus re P. C. Edwards' Letter on Public and Family relations at Stanford University, Gift Procurement Program, Letters re Earl D. Sohm.
  - (T), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 232)
    Harold F. Taggart, Payson J. Treat (re Volunteers for summer quarter), T. A. Bailey, G. W. Pierson (re F. J. Turner and his Frontier Hypothesis).
  - (U - V), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 233)
    Federal Union, Inc., Nathan Van Patten.
  - (W), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 234)
    Lynn White, Jr., Stuart R. Ward (Commonwealth Club of California), Edward White, Win the War - Win the Peace Conference, Clive Warren, R. L. Wilbur, J. B. Weter Memorial Scholarship, James T. Watkins, O. O. Winther, O. H. Wedel, Louis B. Wright, W. M. Rice Institute of Houston, J. H. Watrous, Jr.
  - (XYZ), 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 235)
    A. F. Zimmerman, George Knoles.
  - (A), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 236)
    Henry M. Adams, American Friends Service Committee, Irwin M. Adams, Army and Navy Journal, U. S. History for Army personnel.
  - (B), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 237)
    M. P. Briggs, A. Russell Buchanan, William C. Bark, L. R. Bailey, Harold W. Bradley, Percy W. Bidwell (Council on Foreign relations), Philip Bancroft, John Earle Baker, Eugene H. Byrne.
  - (C), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 238)
    Manoel S. Cardozo, J. Tracy Coker, Paul H. Clyde, Civilian Defense Council, Robert E. Collins, Hardin Craig.
  - (Civilian Defense Council) Minutes of Meetings, Procedures, Rationing., 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - (Committee on Foreign relations), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 240)
    Problems of Dealing with USSR, Britain, China, Axis Powers after War, Lend - Lease.
  - (D), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 241)
    Paul H. Davis, M. E. Deutsch, J. S. Davis (Discussion series on Winning the Peace).
  - (Doctorate of Laws: Wisconsin), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 242)
    C. A. Dykstra, Harry A. Bullis, Edward White, C. P. Higby, J. E. Baker.
  - (E - F), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 243)
    Paul C. Edwards, Edward M. Earle, W. Donald Fletcher.
  - (G), 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 244)
    R. M. P. Grinnell, John Gange (Division of Cultural relations of the Dept. of State), Albert Guerard, Anne Bancroft Graham, R. R. Gros, C. M. Goethe.
  - (H), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 245)
    L. J. Hall, David Harris, John D. M. Hamilton, C. P. Higby, The First-Name Mania by A. H. Withers, Herbert Hoover (Peace Policies), Ann Hackett, ( The Bulwark of American Freedom - Attacks Capitalistic Basis of World Wars).
  - (Hicks: Committee on American History), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 246)
    J. D. Hicks, California Committee for the Study of Education, reports).
  - (School of Humanities), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 247)
    Karl M. Cowdery, Proposed Stanford College, Organization of School of Humanities, M. Savelle, relation of History Dept. to School of Humanities.
  - (I), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 248)
    Yamato Ichihashi (re Detention), Inter-American University of the Air.
  - (International Center), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 249)
    Minutes of Meetings of Directors, E. Guy Talbott.
  - (J), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 250)
    Mrs. D. S. Jordan, Launching of the S.S. David Starr Jordan.
  - (K), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 251)
    John H. Kemble, A. C. Krey, Proposals for International Commission on Education and International Education Organization, Memo on reconstruction of Education in Axis Countries, D. P. Keusseff, Frank J. Klingberg, A. C. Krey.
  - (L), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 252)
    Louis B. Lochner, recommendations of Thomas LaFargue, Ralph H. Lutz.
  - (M), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 253)
    Henry Madden, Beverly McAnear, Frederick Merk, Dudley T. Moorhead.
  - (Mc), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 254)
    Beverly McAnear
  - (N), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 255)
    Congressional Withdrawing of Funds for State Dept. Publications, J. F. Neylan, Netherlands Information Bureau.
  - (Ninth Corps Area Commission on College and University War Problems) Minutes of Meetings, reports., 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 256)
  - (O - P), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 257)